[SPEAKER_01]: in 1938 I was there.
[SPEAKER_01]: And then over to Stratton, Pennsylvania in the Eastern League, and then to Louisville in the American Association, and then to Boston in 1941.
[SPEAKER_02]: Boultree was 1937?
[SPEAKER_02]: Sir?
[SPEAKER_02]: Boultree is 1937?
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, after I finished school I was there from June on.
[SPEAKER_02]: OK. And Canton in 38?
[SPEAKER_02]: Yes, sir.
[SPEAKER_02]: You had a great year at Canton, didn't you?
[SPEAKER_02]: Do you remember your record with the?
[SPEAKER_02]: I won 22 and lost 7.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah?
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, boy.
[SPEAKER_02]: I just did a little study of the Middle Atlantic League in the 30s.
[SPEAKER_02]: And I was doing it for Bob Dayton in particular.
[SPEAKER_02]: But the 38th year, you just dominated the pitching that year.
[SPEAKER_02]: Was Sylvanic with you?
[SPEAKER_02]: Or with Akron that year?
[SPEAKER_01]: Akron was in the league, yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: Frankie Sylvanic had a great year hitting one.
[SPEAKER_02]: You're not sure if that was a year or not.
[SPEAKER_02]: He was there.
[SPEAKER_01]: In fact, they used a small baseball.
[SPEAKER_01]: It seemed like smaller than a regular baseball.
[SPEAKER_01]: Made by Worth.
[SPEAKER_01]: It had white seams.
[SPEAKER_01]: No colored seams like this.
[SPEAKER_01]: And it was what's called a ragged ball.
[SPEAKER_01]: And as I remember, there were three teams in the league with a team average of over 300.
[SPEAKER_01]: There was Portsmouth, Ohio, Oshawa.
[SPEAKER_01]: There was Cardinal Farm, Akron, I believe.
[SPEAKER_01]: There were three teams that had a team batting average of over 300.
[SPEAKER_02]: Whitey Kurowski had a great year.
[SPEAKER_02]: Was he with Portsmouth that year, do you remember?
[SPEAKER_02]: Did he give you any trouble?
[SPEAKER_01]: Smokey Austin was the first baseman.
[SPEAKER_02]: He had a lot of home runs, didn't he?
[SPEAKER_01]: He was the first baseman there.
[SPEAKER_01]: They had a left-handed pitcher at, let me see if I can get my ears straight, Ernie White.
[SPEAKER_01]: with left-hand pictures.
[SPEAKER_01]: Ernie White had as good a stuff as anybody I ever saw at that age.
[SPEAKER_01]: Later with the Colonel, but he had some arm problems.
[SPEAKER_01]: But he was one of the toughest pictures in that, in that lake, as I remember.
[SPEAKER_02]: How were the ballparks in that old lake?
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, the ballpark in Calhoun was just the opposite of Fenway Park.
[SPEAKER_01]: It had a very short right-field fence in Kent.
[SPEAKER_01]: I think it was something like 276 feet to the fence, had a high fence, but it was short and right-field.
[SPEAKER_01]: I don't remember, Johnstown, Pennsylvania.
[SPEAKER_01]: Vernon Stevens and some of them were there.
[SPEAKER_01]: That was a St. Louis Browns-born team when I was in that league.
[SPEAKER_01]: Who was your manager, Ken?
[SPEAKER_01]: He was a left-hand hitter, an outfielder.
[SPEAKER_01]: He still pinch-hits some.
[SPEAKER_01]: A man by the name of Pat Patterson.
[SPEAKER_01]: Kind of a chubby sort of guy.
[SPEAKER_01]: He still took batting practice.
[SPEAKER_01]: He pinch-hits some.
[SPEAKER_01]: He was an old outfielder.
[SPEAKER_01]: But he was relatively young.
[SPEAKER_01]: And he was late playing years at that time.
[SPEAKER_02]: Did you win the pennant that year?
[SPEAKER_01]: Or Canton in 1938?
[SPEAKER_01]: We finished in that league.
[SPEAKER_01]: We were in first place practically the whole year.
[SPEAKER_01]: And the team that was on top on the 4th of July played post to the All-Star team from the rest of the league.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I pitched that ballgame for Kevin and won it that year.
[SPEAKER_01]: And we lost out.
[SPEAKER_01]: the last air show of the season.
[SPEAKER_01]: We did not win.
[SPEAKER_01]: I don't remember.
[SPEAKER_01]: I can't recall now who did win.
[SPEAKER_01]: Which team?
[SPEAKER_01]: I don't remember.
[SPEAKER_01]: It's been a long time.
[SPEAKER_01]: But we were in first place nearly all the year.
[SPEAKER_01]: Most of the Red Sox did win.
[SPEAKER_02]: And you had the playoffs.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well.
[SPEAKER_02]: Didn't you have the Shaughnessy system there?
[SPEAKER_01]: I don't remember the playoff particularly.
[SPEAKER_01]: I don't know whether there was a playoff in that state or not.
[SPEAKER_01]: I don't recall that.
[SPEAKER_01]: There was in Scranton, Pennsylvania, the next year.
[SPEAKER_01]: There was a playoff in the Eastern Leagues.
[SPEAKER_01]: In fact, if my memory serves me correctly,
[SPEAKER_01]: The Scranton team won the playoffs in the Eastern League.
[SPEAKER_01]: Then in Louisville in 1940, we finished in fourth place at one of the worst ball clubs in the league, and seemed we couldn't do anything right.
[SPEAKER_01]: Kansas City won the thing that year, 1940.
[SPEAKER_01]: We backed into fourth place, you might say, the last day of the season.
[SPEAKER_01]: St. Paul lost a doubleheader, and we split a doubleheader.
[SPEAKER_01]: We ran into the playoffs.
[SPEAKER_01]: My mother and daddy had never been out of Texas.
[SPEAKER_01]: They came up to Pennsylvania.
[SPEAKER_01]: My sister, their daughter, had married a fourth man.
[SPEAKER_01]: They came back, too.
[SPEAKER_01]: My dad wanted to come on home.
[SPEAKER_01]: I begged him to stay.
[SPEAKER_01]: I said, I'm pitching tomorrow night against Columbus.
[SPEAKER_01]: And they stayed.
[SPEAKER_01]: And the first and only time in my life I didn't retire back.
[SPEAKER_01]: But we beat Columbus.
[SPEAKER_01]: Then we played Kansas City.
[SPEAKER_01]: Kansas City had a hell of a ballclub.
[SPEAKER_01]: They were
[SPEAKER_01]: They had beaten us 18 out of 22 times that year.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I had been in starting picture and relief picture and everything else.
[SPEAKER_01]: I'd won 7 and lost 11 with this program.
[SPEAKER_01]: I think our top hitter, the top RBI man was Paul Campbell, I believe, and he's had 56 RBIs.
[SPEAKER_01]: That's the kind of ballclub we had.
[SPEAKER_01]: And no prospects on the ballclub.
[SPEAKER_01]: But against Kansas City, what formally started the first game, and at the top of the first inning, I think we got something like five runs.
[SPEAKER_01]: They came up and got four runs in the first inning.
[SPEAKER_01]: I relieved in the sixth inning that game and won it in the tenth inning.
[SPEAKER_01]: The next night, I relieved.
[SPEAKER_01]: and the 7th inning and the 11th inning.
[SPEAKER_01]: That's the first two games.
[SPEAKER_01]: And, of course, we were happy.
[SPEAKER_01]: We beat Kansas City four out of six.
[SPEAKER_01]: And they had Rizzuto and Prady and all the bunch that later went to the Yankees, Johnny Lindell and all that.
[SPEAKER_01]: I beat Kansas City 1-0 to put us in the Little World Series with Baltimore.
[SPEAKER_01]: And when we played Baltimore, we lost four games to two.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I won the only two-ball game for one night.
[SPEAKER_01]: I pitched the whole year at 1-7.
[SPEAKER_01]: I guess the best two minor league teams in baseball.
[SPEAKER_01]: I didn't give up a run against Kansas City.
[SPEAKER_01]: I beat them three times, twice in a league, and once started one to nothing.
[SPEAKER_01]: And then I beat Kansas City, Baltimore, two games.
[SPEAKER_01]: That's what got me a chance with Boston the next day.
[SPEAKER_01]: I would lose seven, won seven all year, and then won five games in two weeks.
[SPEAKER_02]: When did you find out you were going to be brought up by the Red Sox?
[SPEAKER_02]: Sometime that winter did you get a contract or a letter?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, they always notified me.
[SPEAKER_02]: Big thrill, huh?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yes, sir.
[SPEAKER_02]: How was your year with Scranton?
[SPEAKER_01]: Do you remember your one lost record there?
[SPEAKER_01]: I think something like 12 and 7 at Scranton, I believe.
[SPEAKER_02]: Who was your manager?
[SPEAKER_01]: Harry Leibo, L-E-I-B-O-L-D.
[SPEAKER_01]: He was our manager.
[SPEAKER_01]: I suspect the Porsche had been there before that.
[SPEAKER_01]: Now that was two years in a row that Louisville in 1949, 1939 I mean,
[SPEAKER_01]: They had Pee Wee Reese and all that, but they had a pretty good vote.
[SPEAKER_01]: And they had also beat out Kansas City the year before in the playoffs, probably, in the American Association.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, I didn't know exactly what you people wanted, you know.
[SPEAKER_02]: We just wanted to talk baseball.
[SPEAKER_02]: Talk baseball.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, we're great baseball fans.
[SPEAKER_02]: We grew up in Cleveland.
[SPEAKER_02]: We're on Cleveland, you know.
[SPEAKER_02]: We're Cleveland Indian fans.
[SPEAKER_02]: I don't know about Art if he still carries on, carries the torch for Cleveland.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, they had some good ballplay.
[SPEAKER_01]: We had excellent pitching while I was there with the Red Sox.
[SPEAKER_02]: Did you ever get any hookup with Bob Feller in any matches?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yes, sir.
[SPEAKER_01]: I remember one game in Kansas City.
[SPEAKER_01]: This is an attitude.
[SPEAKER_01]: This little baseball digest here, I learned in here.
[SPEAKER_01]: They asked a question about pitchers that were 20-game winners that didn't pitch a shutout.
[SPEAKER_01]: I was listed in there.
[SPEAKER_01]: I won 22 and lost 6 and didn't pitch a shutout.
[SPEAKER_01]: I had an earned run average of 250-something and didn't pitch a shutout.
[SPEAKER_01]: In 1946, I pitched 6 shutouts.
[SPEAKER_01]: I won 20 and lost 11.
[SPEAKER_01]: I pitched six shutouts, four of them wanted nothing.
[SPEAKER_01]: And a big Bob Feller wanted nothing in Cleveland.
[SPEAKER_01]: And four days later, we pitched on four days, three days straight, you don't think.
[SPEAKER_01]: Now everybody's gone to five days.
[SPEAKER_02]: They got to rest their arms today.
[SPEAKER_01]: I pitched all the time on four days.
[SPEAKER_01]: I like this.
[SPEAKER_01]: Big Feller wanted nothing in Cleveland.
[SPEAKER_01]: Four days later in Detroit, I beat Freddie Hutchinson one night.
[SPEAKER_01]: And found an oddity here.
[SPEAKER_01]: I'm not bragging or propping off this statement.
[SPEAKER_01]: In those two games, the longest ball hit to win a ball game was a pop fly to the first baseman.
[SPEAKER_01]: With Bobby Doerr, had a lifetime batting average against a fellow
[SPEAKER_01]: of 4.27.
[SPEAKER_01]: And in fact, Feller pitched several one-hit games.
[SPEAKER_01]: Doerr broke up two of them when Feller was pitching.
[SPEAKER_01]: He was a good fastball hitter.
[SPEAKER_01]: Bobby Doerr tripled in the seventh inning as him against Feller with one out.
[SPEAKER_01]: Rudy York hit a pop fly over by behind first base.
[SPEAKER_01]: thrown in his coach in the third tailing door, tag up and go, tag up and go.
[SPEAKER_01]: Boy by the name of Hogshick, I believe, was the first baseman.
[SPEAKER_01]: Was that Elan Hogshick or called him Hoghead?
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, Fleming, Fleming was his name.
[SPEAKER_00]: Fleming, Les Fleming.
[SPEAKER_01]: He was Fleming's first baseman.
[SPEAKER_01]: He caught this ball in an awkward position over behind the dugout.
[SPEAKER_01]: And Boudreaux came in, not thinking that Doar was going to try to go.
[SPEAKER_01]: Boudreaux cut the throw off and Doerr slinked in.
[SPEAKER_01]: I believe he would have made it anyway.
[SPEAKER_01]: But here was Cronin's thinking against Feller, this ball is carved, it's two out.
[SPEAKER_01]: You've got to take a chance, you've got to gamble.
[SPEAKER_01]: But he kept telling Doerr, tie that to Doerr.
[SPEAKER_01]: And he did.
[SPEAKER_01]: And that's the way the run was going.
[SPEAKER_01]: Against Freddie Hutchinson and the Trudge, they walked Ted Williamson, basically.
[SPEAKER_01]: So the only ball hit to get in to win two games, won nothing, was foul balls.
[SPEAKER_01]: Kind of an odd situation.
[SPEAKER_01]: Then I beat Cleveland again, won nothing.
[SPEAKER_01]: On Friday the 13th of September, 1946, we had about a 13-14 game lead.
[SPEAKER_01]: And it's kind of an odd situation here.
[SPEAKER_01]: Mr. Tom Yolke had always aspired to winning a championship.
[SPEAKER_01]: He tried to buy a championship.
[SPEAKER_01]: He bought Joe Cronin for $250.
[SPEAKER_01]: He bought Jimmy Foxx.
[SPEAKER_01]: He bought Lefty Grove in 1934.
[SPEAKER_01]: This is 1946.
[SPEAKER_01]: We needed to win one game.
[SPEAKER_01]: We went to Philadelphia on the road.
[SPEAKER_01]: We lost four straight Philadelphia.
[SPEAKER_01]: They had all the champagne and everything ready to celebrate.
[SPEAKER_01]: And on Sunday in Philadelphia, blue first, I said, 420 game winners, we're pitching this doubleheader, the last two games.
[SPEAKER_01]: We lost four straight.
[SPEAKER_01]: They said, well, Mr. York, somebody said, well, we're celebrating Detroit.
[SPEAKER_01]: That's a better town, a better deal than everything else.
[SPEAKER_01]: They load the stuff up and we go to Detroit.
[SPEAKER_01]: And we lost a pretty straight play.
[SPEAKER_01]: There was no choking up or anything.
[SPEAKER_01]: We just got the maybe a little complacent.
[SPEAKER_01]: I don't know, but those things will happen.
[SPEAKER_01]: And we lost the three games there.
[SPEAKER_01]: On the 13th of September, just so happens I remember the date, Friday the 13th, a big Cleveland one to nothing in Old League Park, one of the last games played in Old League Park.
[SPEAKER_01]: Old League Park was kind of like the Canton ballpark, short right field.
[SPEAKER_01]: In this ballgame, the first inning, two out, nobody on.
[SPEAKER_01]: They had the Williams shift on, the Blue Grove shift or whatever you call it.
[SPEAKER_01]: Pat Seary in left field was way over the center.
[SPEAKER_01]: Ted hit a ball over the third baseman's head.
[SPEAKER_01]: It rolled all the way into foul territory.
[SPEAKER_01]: He circled the bases, home run inside the park, and that's the way the game ended.
[SPEAKER_01]: Threw out nobody on him the first inning.
[SPEAKER_01]: And that was the game that clinched the pennant.
[SPEAKER_02]: You had your champagne with you then.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yes.
[SPEAKER_01]: But somebody said, must be August.
[SPEAKER_01]: He promised if we had one opponent, he wouldn't put one ball player in each room.
[SPEAKER_01]: He said he'd put one ball player on each floor.
[SPEAKER_01]: That's just baseball talk.
[SPEAKER_01]: I don't know how to say it.
[SPEAKER_01]: He could afford it, though.
[SPEAKER_01]: He certainly could have.
[SPEAKER_02]: Did you ever have any contract troubles with him?
[SPEAKER_01]: No, sir.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, kind of an unusual situation here.
[SPEAKER_01]: Mr. Yawkey owned the ball club, laptop and barrel, no other stockholder or shareholder of anything.
[SPEAKER_01]: But he had other answers.
[SPEAKER_01]: Mining answers.
[SPEAKER_01]: Lumber answers.
[SPEAKER_01]: Real estate answers.
[SPEAKER_01]: Each one, and the Boston American League Baseball Club, all of these are separate entities.
[SPEAKER_01]: And Eddie Collins was a gentleman, and the staff,
[SPEAKER_01]: It was a separate entity, and Mr. Yawkey did not, he relinquished pretty much control of the boat.
[SPEAKER_01]: He was a very generous man, a very kind-hearted man, a real sportsman, somewhat of a philanthropist, hero worshiper.
[SPEAKER_01]: He was an orphan boy.
[SPEAKER_01]: He was raised
[SPEAKER_01]: by someone, the Maven family that owned the Detroit ball club way back, way back then.
[SPEAKER_01]: And he was, he loved baseball.
[SPEAKER_01]: He went to Yale, tried to play.
[SPEAKER_01]: He was a hero worshiper.
[SPEAKER_01]: If he'd have had his own way, he would have played these ball players like Ted Williams and, you know, big fantastic challenges.
[SPEAKER_01]: However, it was run strictly on a business order.
[SPEAKER_01]: The people running the ball club wanted to be successful, you know.
[SPEAKER_01]: And as far as I know, some information that I got inside was that the Red Sox made money every year they played.
[SPEAKER_01]: They didn't lose money.
[SPEAKER_01]: Mr. Yawkey would not have cared.
[SPEAKER_01]: But of course, they'd take pride in their work and management and all.
[SPEAKER_01]: And they did.
[SPEAKER_01]: They'd tell me that they made
[SPEAKER_01]: money all over, throughout the evening, during the day.
[SPEAKER_01]: I remember in 1944, I was with the Red Sox.
[SPEAKER_01]: Time came for me to go into the service, and I was called, this was on the, to go into the service and
[SPEAKER_01]: It looked like Boston was right up to it.
[SPEAKER_01]: And they had a chance to win.
[SPEAKER_01]: When I left, they said they shorted pitchers.
[SPEAKER_01]: They had two boys out on the West Coast that were having good years that were for sale.
[SPEAKER_01]: That's when some of the teams in the Pacific Coast League were independent.
[SPEAKER_01]: There was two boys out there that could
[SPEAKER_01]: that was having good years, it was for sale.
[SPEAKER_01]: The scouting reports were not good on these two.
[SPEAKER_01]: And that's the story I get.
[SPEAKER_01]: Mr. Yelkey said, the hell with the Boston American League Baseball Company.
[SPEAKER_01]: He wrote his personal check for $100,000 for those two players.
[SPEAKER_01]: And it so happened that one of the players
[SPEAKER_01]: was 31 years old, been pitching for 10 or 12 years.
[SPEAKER_01]: He won one game for Boston.
[SPEAKER_01]: He was one of these guys that smoked cigars and drank ball of micas and all that, you know.
[SPEAKER_01]: The other boy was a left-hander, Clem Draswood, a left-handed pitcher that stayed with Boston.
[SPEAKER_01]: He couldn't black the eye, throwing hard, but he was a relief pitcher.
[SPEAKER_01]: He stayed with Boston for several years.
[SPEAKER_01]: That's the two boys.
[SPEAKER_01]: Who was the other one?
[SPEAKER_01]: This is to just give you
[SPEAKER_01]: and now they have Mr. Yelkey operating the boat.
[SPEAKER_01]: That's the story I get.
[SPEAKER_01]: But he said to hell with the Baltimore League baseball team.
[SPEAKER_02]: He overruled his council.
[SPEAKER_01]: He'd been reading the newspapers.
[SPEAKER_02]: So he bought them with his own kids.
[SPEAKER_02]: Dreisschwerd was one.
[SPEAKER_02]: Who was the other?
[SPEAKER_01]: Rex Cecil was the other kid.
[SPEAKER_01]: Another forgettable name.
[SPEAKER_02]: Dreisschwerd had a great minor league record though, didn't he?
[SPEAKER_02]: Dreisschert had a long minor league career.
[SPEAKER_01]: Anyhow, those two were for sale, but the Red Sox spouse went out and watched them study directly, and they did not recommend them.
[SPEAKER_01]: And Mr. Yoffe just said, that's what I'd say, he just said, to hell with Boston-Mercury League Baseball Club.
[SPEAKER_01]: He played for them and sat.
[SPEAKER_01]: But Cecil didn't even last.
[SPEAKER_01]: I mean, he didn't stay there.
[SPEAKER_01]: He was gone when we came back in 1946.
[SPEAKER_01]: But Dravard was.
[SPEAKER_01]: I'll show you a picture here.
[SPEAKER_01]: This is the 1946 written.
[SPEAKER_01]: Let's see, we're looking for Dravard.
[SPEAKER_01]: He's here somewhere.
[SPEAKER_01]: Next to Metcalfe.
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: Joe Dobson, yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: Why'd we ever get rid of him?
[SPEAKER_00]: I'm talking in Cleveland terms now.
[SPEAKER_00]: I was wondering why Cleveland ever got rid of Joe Dobson.
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, I don't know.
[SPEAKER_02]: Bill Zuber, I met him out in Amana, out in Iowa there.
[SPEAKER_02]: Oh, yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: Big restaurants out there.
[SPEAKER_01]: I'll tell you what, there was a man who could throw hard.
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: He could throw just as hard as anybody, but he had no control.
[SPEAKER_01]: He'd walk, somebody beat himself, that's all.
[SPEAKER_00]: You know, I'm astounded.
[SPEAKER_00]: I see so many former Indians there.
[SPEAKER_00]: Zuber, Bagby, Dobson, Metcovich.
[SPEAKER_00]: He might have been there before.
[SPEAKER_00]: I don't think Metcovich ever went to Cleveland.
[SPEAKER_00]: Maybe later.
[SPEAKER_00]: In 1948, yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was in the farm system.
[SPEAKER_00]: He came up to the race.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, right.
[SPEAKER_01]: That's right.
[SPEAKER_01]: Don Gutters was the old St. Louis guy.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: Hankie Higgins, of course.
[SPEAKER_01]: All those boys are gone.
[SPEAKER_01]: Last year, we had an old-timers game in Boston.
[SPEAKER_01]: They honored the 1946 World Series team.
[SPEAKER_01]: And there's 19, there's 21 of these boys still living.
[SPEAKER_01]: There was 19 of them back at this.
[SPEAKER_01]: They honored the 1946 World Series team.
[SPEAKER_01]: This is what they did.
[SPEAKER_01]: American League Champions 1946.
[SPEAKER_01]: They gave us this watch.
[SPEAKER_01]: Two years ago I was up in Boston and the old-timers game, they gave us this watch for the old-timers game.
[SPEAKER_01]: It's a special made watch for Hamilton with the Red Sox engraved on the back.
[SPEAKER_01]: I keep up with the Red Sox all the time.
[SPEAKER_01]: I go down, we do, what, I go down to Spring Training every year, we do it in Waterhaven, have been, and seagull games down there, go to Boston, Paisley.
[SPEAKER_01]: I've got satellite fish here in my yard, and I watch all of that stuff.
[SPEAKER_01]: Is that right?
[SPEAKER_01]: I see them all the time, all the games.
[SPEAKER_01]: The door was in,
[SPEAKER_01]: It was in already last October, the Baseball Hall of Fame.
[SPEAKER_01]: At long last.
[SPEAKER_01]: Cronin and Williams were already in.
[SPEAKER_01]: I was fortunate.
[SPEAKER_01]: I played with five Hall of Famers.
[SPEAKER_01]: There's two that were already through here.
[SPEAKER_01]: Rudy York, I mean, Jimmy Fox and Lefty Grove.
[SPEAKER_01]: They were through before this, but I played with them.
[SPEAKER_01]: In other words, I was fortunate enough to have played with them.
[SPEAKER_02]: Were you with Lefty Grove when he won his 300th game?
[SPEAKER_02]: Yes.
[SPEAKER_00]: He had a hard time getting it, though, didn't he?
[SPEAKER_00]: It was like an early win.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: He and Early win the same thing.
[SPEAKER_01]: Johnny Pesky still was both there.
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, he's been all these years.
[SPEAKER_02]: John Paveskovich.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, is that Dale Baker?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, it must be.
[SPEAKER_00]: Dale Baker.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, the manager.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, Detroit.
[SPEAKER_01]: Detroit, yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: Charlie Wagner still was above that.
[SPEAKER_01]: Broadway Charlie.
[SPEAKER_01]: How did he get that nickname?
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, Charlie was a fancy damn little guy, you know, a man.
[SPEAKER_01]: Every morning when he was on the road, he'd call the operator and see what the weather was going to be like, and he'd dress fancy there on Broadway.
[SPEAKER_01]: He was a bachelor at the time, and he changed suits two or three times a day and all that kind of stuff.
[SPEAKER_01]: Was there another catcher, Hal Wagner?
[SPEAKER_01]: Sir?
[SPEAKER_01]: Wasn't there another catcher, Hal Wagner?
[SPEAKER_01]: Hal Wagner was a catcher.
[SPEAKER_01]: Hal's in here somewhere.
[SPEAKER_01]: Is he?
[SPEAKER_01]: I'll find him in a minute.
[SPEAKER_01]: He's got to be.
[SPEAKER_00]: There it is, second row I guess, middle row number eight.
[SPEAKER_02]: Resume, shall we, in here?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, let's go back to that.
[SPEAKER_01]: I just thought maybe we'd talk about these people.
[SPEAKER_02]: Do you have a scrapbook?
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, I've got a ton.
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, you do?
[SPEAKER_02]: How about the 46 World Series?
[SPEAKER_02]: Don't you want to talk about that?
[SPEAKER_02]: Who was pitching when Slaughter made his great run?
[SPEAKER_01]: Bob Singer.
[SPEAKER_01]: He was an old National League relief pitcher we got from Pittsburgh.
[SPEAKER_01]: At the time that Slaughter scored, I was in the bullpen.
[SPEAKER_01]: I had pitched four and two-thirds innings the day before.
[SPEAKER_01]: in the sixth game and released.
[SPEAKER_01]: I pitched the opening game.
[SPEAKER_01]: We won the opening game 3-2 in the 10th inning.
[SPEAKER_01]: Rudy York hit a home run off of Howard Corlett in the 10th.
[SPEAKER_01]: I was not the winning pitcher.
[SPEAKER_01]: I was taken out for a hitter in the 8th inning with a tying run on third.
[SPEAKER_01]: Tom McBride got the base hit and scored the tying run.
[SPEAKER_01]: Earl Johnson was the pitcher.
[SPEAKER_01]: came in, Earl was, this is the first one, Earl was the winning pitcher when New York hit the home run.
[SPEAKER_01]: I started the fourth game.
[SPEAKER_01]: I didn't do anything right.
[SPEAKER_01]: And they did everything right.
[SPEAKER_01]: We used four or five pitchers.
[SPEAKER_01]: They got 15 or 18 hits, you know, one of those days.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I pitched four and two-thirds innings the sixth game.
[SPEAKER_01]: And then the seventh game, they had
[SPEAKER_01]: And DiMaggio hit a double.
[SPEAKER_01]: He drove in two runs.
[SPEAKER_01]: They tied the score.
[SPEAKER_01]: And as DiMaggio was playing on bad luck, they didn't know it.
[SPEAKER_01]: They had it wrapped.
[SPEAKER_01]: As he rounded first, he pulled this muscle.
[SPEAKER_01]: He got to second.
[SPEAKER_01]: They took him out for a runner.
[SPEAKER_01]: He was hurt.
[SPEAKER_01]: And Leon Culbertson, whose picture you can see here, was playing center field at the time, in place of DiMaggio.
[SPEAKER_01]: And when this happened, I was in the bullpen, and there was two pitchers throwing, the left-hander Earl Johnson and the right-hander Bob Clancy.
[SPEAKER_01]: Cronin's coaching at third, and he did this and this, tall, that's me.
[SPEAKER_01]: But I think for sure that he wants a left-handed or right-handed pitcher.
[SPEAKER_01]: So I said, clear down and start throwing.
[SPEAKER_01]: And Cronin did this and the whole changeover.
[SPEAKER_01]: And so I took Earl Johnson's place.
[SPEAKER_01]: And then Cronin gives me this, hurry,
[SPEAKER_01]: You know.
[SPEAKER_01]: So I'm, while this is happening, when slaughter was on, I'm warming up.
[SPEAKER_01]: I didn't see the play.
[SPEAKER_01]: I didn't see that exactly when the ball was hit or something.
[SPEAKER_01]: But I know exactly, maybe watching it.
[SPEAKER_01]: But I thought I was going to be the pitcher, since he sat down Johnson.
[SPEAKER_01]: He had the cleaner warming up already anyway.
[SPEAKER_01]: And when he got me up and gave me the hurry,
[SPEAKER_01]: Joe told me later that he was fully intended to bring me in.
[SPEAKER_01]: But then he decided two things, that I had pitched four and two-thirds innings the day before.
[SPEAKER_01]: He changed his mind, by the way.
[SPEAKER_01]: He went with Klinger.
[SPEAKER_01]: Because Klinger was playing in the National League, he was familiar with the National League hitters, you know.
[SPEAKER_01]: But the way I saw the play, everybody said,
[SPEAKER_01]: There's four triders in Boston when we're done, Florida and all that.
[SPEAKER_01]: The way I, the hit and run was on, Harry Walker was the batter.
[SPEAKER_01]: And Slaughter is running with the pitch.
[SPEAKER_01]: Harry Walker hit a land drive to the left center field.
[SPEAKER_01]: The play is right in front of Slaughter.
[SPEAKER_01]: Because he's running.
[SPEAKER_01]: Slaughter made up the way I see it.
[SPEAKER_01]: sort of made up his mind right then that the ball was going to go through because DiMaggio wasn't out there, and that he was going to score.
[SPEAKER_01]: And Carver backhanded the ball on the second half out here.
[SPEAKER_01]: He relayed the ball in to Pesky, and Slaughter has just now reached third base.
[SPEAKER_01]: And Pesky, as he turned, he started to cough and throw, as I see.
[SPEAKER_01]: He thought that Slaughter was going to make the turn and come back.
[SPEAKER_01]: You know, just bluff and try and throw the throw.
[SPEAKER_01]: But then he kind of popped again.
[SPEAKER_01]: I could see this.
[SPEAKER_01]: It could happen to anybody.
[SPEAKER_01]: He made a poor throw to the plate.
[SPEAKER_01]: However, Slaughter, I think, for this time, would have scored anyway.
[SPEAKER_02]: He never broke stride, did he?
[SPEAKER_02]: Slaughter never broke stride.
[SPEAKER_01]: Never broke stride.
[SPEAKER_01]: The coach was trying his best to hold him up and everything else.
[SPEAKER_01]: But that's the reason I said Slaughter made up his mind.
[SPEAKER_01]: Regardless, this way I see it.
[SPEAKER_01]: Regardless, Pesky says he didn't.
[SPEAKER_01]: Some of us, Pesky can't blame Bobby Doerr for not helping him, not telling him, not showing him, you know, calling his play.
[SPEAKER_01]: Because his backers, when he's fielding the puck, cut off the backers.
[SPEAKER_01]: The way I see it, of course, I'm not second-guessing.
[SPEAKER_01]: I'm just questioning, should have thrown the ball ahead of the run, you know, not way.
[SPEAKER_01]: You see, he turned around.
[SPEAKER_01]: He should have thrown hard.
[SPEAKER_01]: And he didn't.
[SPEAKER_01]: I've done this on the mound.
[SPEAKER_01]: One hopper back to me quick.
[SPEAKER_01]: I've turned to throw the second, the infielders haven't got there yet.
[SPEAKER_01]: In fact, the second time I've thrown the damn ball.
[SPEAKER_01]: That's what happened to Pesky up there.
[SPEAKER_01]: You know, you lose your coordination sometimes.
[SPEAKER_01]: And he did not make a good throw.
[SPEAKER_01]: It wasn't Pesky's good throw.
[SPEAKER_01]: And it was all for the play.
[SPEAKER_01]: But slaughter had made up his mind.
[SPEAKER_01]: But the ball, I think he could visualize the ball going to the wall and he's going to throw it away.
[SPEAKER_01]: So that's the way I saw the play.
[SPEAKER_01]: But I was in the bullpen warming up.
[SPEAKER_01]: Now, that pitch to throw him out would have been a tie ball game.
[SPEAKER_01]: We might still be playing.
[SPEAKER_02]: I don't know.
[SPEAKER_01]: Who knows what's going to happen?
[SPEAKER_01]: We don't know.
[SPEAKER_02]: I was usual to pitch to.
[SPEAKER_01]: New Jersey was tough.
[SPEAKER_01]: In 1946, when we won this thing, on a big Cleveland, we went from there to Chicago.
[SPEAKER_01]: We started the series in Westland, Detroit, to Cleveland, to Chicago.
[SPEAKER_01]: When we got to Chicago, I pitched there, and
[SPEAKER_01]: The boys, we had a free game scheduled in St. Louis.
[SPEAKER_01]: Several of us went back to Boston.
[SPEAKER_01]: We won the pennant.
[SPEAKER_01]: They didn't need us.
[SPEAKER_01]: A couple of starting pitchers and two or three others.
[SPEAKER_01]: We went back to Boston.
[SPEAKER_01]: The Boston Braves were playing in the St. Louis Cardinals.
[SPEAKER_01]: And we found scouting there.
[SPEAKER_01]: And the night that I was there,
[SPEAKER_01]: Slaughter got four hits that night.
[SPEAKER_01]: And the way it looked to me, Slaughter, most of the hits he got, balls were way from him, out over the plate.
[SPEAKER_01]: And my idea of pitching to Slaughter then, having watched this ball game, was to
[SPEAKER_01]: Waste the fastball, don't give him the ball away so that he can hit.
[SPEAKER_01]: Hit him in.
[SPEAKER_01]: The first time up, I came inside with the slider, propped up first, just propped up the infield.
[SPEAKER_01]: The next, I started him the next time up the same way, a good fastball away so he can come back in, ground ball second base.
[SPEAKER_01]: The third time, same thing, I pitched him outside, come back in.
[SPEAKER_01]: I can't imitate Slaughter's play, but anyway, instead of going here, he's smarter than I was.
[SPEAKER_02]: He comes, he's looking for this pitch, he comes here, and he's the damnedest line driver against the screen for two bases.
[SPEAKER_01]: Later in the ballgame, I got the first, I don't know how, but I told Slaughter, I said, you're smarter than me.
[SPEAKER_01]: You know, he was thinking just, he knew.
[SPEAKER_01]: Now a lot of it was not that noticeable, wasn't it?
[SPEAKER_01]: But in that series, I played against Slaughter,
[SPEAKER_01]: and some of these guys, overseas.
[SPEAKER_01]: Howard Parlette and Slaughter was on the, there was three teams, Air Force teams.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I pitched against Slaughter all the time over there.
[SPEAKER_01]: They knew me with World Series.
[SPEAKER_01]: Figured I'm a fastball pitcher, which I sure do.
[SPEAKER_01]: I guess.
[SPEAKER_01]: It just so happened that for once I had a halfway decent curveball.
[SPEAKER_01]: I threw a lot more furs and changeups in that opening game of the series than I usually do.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I was reasonably successful.
[SPEAKER_01]: So starting the fourth game, when I didn't do any good, instead of going back to my ballgame, to pitch my ballgame, I argued with myself.
[SPEAKER_01]: Should I pitch?
[SPEAKER_01]: But then I said, well, I was successful pitching that way, so I'm going to try it again.
[SPEAKER_01]: And it didn't work.
[SPEAKER_01]: I didn't have a curve ball.
[SPEAKER_01]: In other words, I'm pitching against myself, really, my strength, when I pitched the first game.
[SPEAKER_01]: I tried to pitch the same way the second time, and it didn't get by me.
[SPEAKER_00]: You mentioned the slider.
[SPEAKER_00]: Did you have a slider?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yes, sir.
[SPEAKER_01]: I threw the slider.
[SPEAKER_01]: was probably my best pitcher of the group, really.
[SPEAKER_01]: I learned to throw the sliders.
[SPEAKER_01]: I never did have a good curveball to this day.
[SPEAKER_01]: When I was pitching in the American Association, Bill Burwell was an old pitcher, was our manager.
[SPEAKER_01]: I got kicked one night, home run.
[SPEAKER_01]: Burwell asked me.
[SPEAKER_01]: Burwell had pitched for 20 years in the Coast League, not in the Base League.
[SPEAKER_01]: He was a pitcher.
[SPEAKER_01]: I learned something from him.
[SPEAKER_01]: But he asked me, he said, what did you throw him?
[SPEAKER_01]: I said, he hit the damn curve ball.
[SPEAKER_01]: He said, in a spot like that where it beats you, don't ever throw that damn nickel curve of yours again.
[SPEAKER_01]: He said, that's just like feeding him an ice cream soda with whipped cream and nuts and a cherry on top.
[SPEAKER_01]: Whenever you throw that nickel curve, that's, I'll just tell you, that's the kind of curve ball it is.
[SPEAKER_01]: But I did
[SPEAKER_01]: The slider was the easiest pitch to throw.
[SPEAKER_01]: I didn't know 63 hard on the arm.
[SPEAKER_01]: I could throw a decent curveball if I start to warm up for ballgame and I'm just loose, not throwing hard.
[SPEAKER_01]: I could throw a decent curveball.
[SPEAKER_01]: But when I went on up to the maximum speed, I'd lose that curveball.
[SPEAKER_01]: I couldn't get the right rotation.
[SPEAKER_01]: I worked on it.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I never had a decent change.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I finally developed a little old nickel screwball that I used.
[SPEAKER_01]: I tried this and Jimmy Fox had an excellent screwball.
[SPEAKER_01]: It wasn't even... Jimmy caught some play first base and all that.
[SPEAKER_01]: Had an excellent screwball.
[SPEAKER_01]: Mike Reba on our ball pitch, the screwball pitcher on the relief pitch.
[SPEAKER_01]: I tried.
[SPEAKER_01]: I never could have.
[SPEAKER_01]: I hurt my arm and couldn't get it.
[SPEAKER_01]: It took me two years to learn where I could get it down and use it.
[SPEAKER_01]: To take a baseball, I would separate the fingers a little bit and as I released the ball, I'd get the reverse spin from underneath this finger with this finger off.
[SPEAKER_01]: And it wasn't nothing but it didn't break me.
[SPEAKER_01]: It was more or less a tangent.
[SPEAKER_01]: several years I got this.
[SPEAKER_01]: One is a crash ball, two is a curve, three is either, if it's a right-handed batter, it's an automatic slider.
[SPEAKER_01]: Three, if it's a left-hand hitter, it's a screwball.
[SPEAKER_01]: I used the one side.
[SPEAKER_01]: The screwball I had didn't fool anybody except the speed of the ball.
[SPEAKER_01]: But I got some left-hand hitters out,
[SPEAKER_01]: because it acted as a change of pace.
[SPEAKER_01]: I threw two fastballs, one across field, overhand.
[SPEAKER_01]: That's just straight fastball.
[SPEAKER_01]: I learned early in my career, I learned to turn the ball over, catch the ball in the narrow part of the ball with the fingers out a little more, grip it tight.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I threw a little dinky center.
[SPEAKER_01]: That was my best skill.
[SPEAKER_01]: practice.
[SPEAKER_01]: But if, for example, a man on third and when I fly ball or something, I get two strikes, I would come across the seam and try to ride and pass the ball, put the strike down.
[SPEAKER_01]: But the majority of the pitches I play are with the seams, with a little bit of the seam.
[SPEAKER_01]: The ball is round, the bat's round, they tell you to hit it square.
[SPEAKER_01]: You don't have to have the big foot.
[SPEAKER_01]: It's the quick break
[SPEAKER_01]: Now, I didn't have any kind of a sinking ball like Bob Stanley or some of these real sinker ball pitchers.
[SPEAKER_01]: My ball was quicker and harder.
[SPEAKER_01]: How fast did you throw?
[SPEAKER_02]: Did they measure speeds in those days?
[SPEAKER_01]: They didn't.
[SPEAKER_01]: They tried.
[SPEAKER_01]: It wasn't accurate.
[SPEAKER_01]: They had these ray guns now that can tell you exactly.
[SPEAKER_01]: They tried to clock Bob Feller.
[SPEAKER_01]: They said they clocked him at 100 miles an hour or thereabouts.
[SPEAKER_01]: It wasn't accurate.
[SPEAKER_01]: They said it wasn't accurate.
[SPEAKER_01]: There's some way they had to throw the ball, they had to go through here, break this and break this, and the ball went through.
[SPEAKER_01]: They timed it that way.
[SPEAKER_01]: It wasn't accurate.
[SPEAKER_01]: But they said that the best, the closest they could get, Cullars could throw about a hundred miles an hour.
[SPEAKER_01]: And there's some, Nolan Ryan can throw about, or did throw about as far as Cullars.
[SPEAKER_01]: And there's a lot of guys now that are throwing 95 to 97 pretty active.
[SPEAKER_01]: That's Roger Clements, Red Sox, and this and that kind of thing, that are throwing 95 to 97.
[SPEAKER_01]: Bruce Gossage, you know, one of these, those kind of guys throwing 96, 97.
[SPEAKER_01]: I could throw except for fellas.
[SPEAKER_01]: Within the top five pitchers, I could throw right along with them.
[SPEAKER_02]: You say it'd be over 90 probably?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yes, definitely.
[SPEAKER_01]: In other words, if there's anybody else throwing over 90, I could throw just right along.
[SPEAKER_01]: The main thing that I had going for me was control.
[SPEAKER_01]: I had excellent control.
[SPEAKER_01]: I didn't walk anybody.
[SPEAKER_01]: Never wild-fished.
[SPEAKER_01]: Never wild-fished a man.
[SPEAKER_01]: Never even wild-fished a man to settle.
[SPEAKER_01]: Never.
[SPEAKER_01]: Very seldom walked anybody.
[SPEAKER_00]: How did you acquire it?
[SPEAKER_01]: Natural ability, I guess.
[SPEAKER_01]: And from the time I was six, seven years old, I liked to throw.
[SPEAKER_01]: I was throwing rocks and throwing at everything.
[SPEAKER_01]: Walked three miles to school on a gravel road.
[SPEAKER_01]: I'm not supposed to throw anything with gravel rocks.
[SPEAKER_01]: Throwing at rabbits and birds and everything else.
[SPEAKER_01]: But a lot of it is natural ability.
[SPEAKER_01]: My dad could throw well.
[SPEAKER_01]: He played some semi-pro ball way back.
[SPEAKER_01]: And my mother was kind of outdoored.
[SPEAKER_01]: She was accurate with his coordination.
[SPEAKER_01]: Some of it, yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: You can train yourself.
[SPEAKER_01]: I don't know why.
[SPEAKER_01]: But I've seen a lot of pictures, with all their belts in the world.
[SPEAKER_01]: But if you can't control it, it's no good.
[SPEAKER_01]: Like Bill Zubrin here, Detroit had a boy that could throw as hard as anybody.
[SPEAKER_01]: Or this fella, I don't care who, Luke Kretlow, and he'd never beat anybody hard enough.
[SPEAKER_01]: Ken Chase, a left-handed pitcher that we had, everybody tried.
[SPEAKER_01]: Ken Chase, a left-handed pitcher, could throw as hard as anybody.
[SPEAKER_01]: But he couldn't get it over, consistently.
[SPEAKER_00]: I remember another one of the Indians, a white name, I can't remember his name.
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: Back off.
[SPEAKER_01]: It takes so much time to break this.
[SPEAKER_01]: Either, what I was thinking, either I had somebody beat and over with it in two hours,
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, I was gone earlier, wasn't taking a shot.
[SPEAKER_01]: But I like, not real fast, but I want it to pitch.
[SPEAKER_01]: If I'm going to, I want the catcher to get me that ball back.
[SPEAKER_01]: I don't want any distractions.
[SPEAKER_01]: If I just miss with a pitch, the quicker I can get it back and concentrating on where that ball is, the better.
[SPEAKER_01]: I don't want to do all this a lot, you know.
[SPEAKER_01]: Enfielders coming in and all that.
[SPEAKER_02]: How did the umpires treat you?
[SPEAKER_02]: Or how did you... Have any problems with umpires?
[SPEAKER_01]: No.
[SPEAKER_01]: Not particularly.
[SPEAKER_01]: I used to...
[SPEAKER_01]: I tried to get along with the umpire and the sports officer.
[SPEAKER_01]: I was always kidding with the umpire a little bit.
[SPEAKER_01]: Trying to be a good guy.
[SPEAKER_01]: Wasn't begging for anything.
[SPEAKER_01]: But they're human, I mean.
[SPEAKER_01]: Umpires have got to think this job.
[SPEAKER_01]: A real tough job.
[SPEAKER_01]: If I pitch a nine-inning ballgame, I hardly ever threw a hundred pitches.
[SPEAKER_01]: Anywhere from 85 to 95 for real.
[SPEAKER_01]: But out of that 95 pitches, I would make, if I were my own judge, I threw an umpire in my own ballgame,
[SPEAKER_01]: I've made anywhere from five to ten pitches for that ball.
[SPEAKER_01]: But I don't know whether it was a strike or a ball.
[SPEAKER_01]: The outside part of the plate is here.
[SPEAKER_01]: I don't know whether that ball was high enough or whether it hit a part of the plate.
[SPEAKER_01]: But he's got the coach.
[SPEAKER_00]: The man back here's got the coach.
[SPEAKER_01]: I don't know myself.
[SPEAKER_01]: If I were on par in my own game, in my own honesty, I don't know what this ball is, sir.
[SPEAKER_01]: I've seen this.
[SPEAKER_01]: The Red Sox sitting here.
[SPEAKER_01]: Twenty-five players on a team, nine players.
[SPEAKER_01]: Bunch of us sitting on a bench.
[SPEAKER_01]: First base is right here.
[SPEAKER_01]: I've seen a close play in first base.
[SPEAKER_01]: The six of us sitting here looking at it.
[SPEAKER_01]: Three of us said he was out and three of us said he was safe.
[SPEAKER_01]: In our own hearts and minds, you know, just discussing.
[SPEAKER_01]: That poor devil got to college, right then and there.
[SPEAKER_01]: On a real close play, you know.
[SPEAKER_01]: No instant replay.
[SPEAKER_01]: Vampires make mistakes, no doubt about it.
[SPEAKER_02]: You had such good control, though, that there probably wasn't that much of a problem with vampires.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, I'll tell you what.
[SPEAKER_01]: I kind of had a groove.
[SPEAKER_01]: I pitched left-handers right on the outside for it.
[SPEAKER_01]: And the only objection when I asked, the only play where I cried about it,
[SPEAKER_01]: left-hand hitters up here, and I'm fixing outside the umpire looking over.
[SPEAKER_01]: They have given me some pictures out there.
[SPEAKER_01]: It's never hard to take one away.
[SPEAKER_00]: But I get two strikes, and I come in on a left-hander.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I get what I think is a good portion of the play above the net.
[SPEAKER_01]: And first, I didn't get it.
[SPEAKER_01]: That was a pitch I needed for a strikeout with two strikes.
[SPEAKER_01]: I talked to him for a second.
[SPEAKER_01]: I said, you've given me these pictures, you don't question me about that.
[SPEAKER_01]: But I said, I don't know.
[SPEAKER_01]: That's the plot that he had going on.
[SPEAKER_02]: Did Ted Williams get the break on some doubtful pictures you think because he had such a good eye?
[SPEAKER_01]: Probably.
[SPEAKER_01]: with certain umpires.
[SPEAKER_01]: In other words, a lot of people.
[SPEAKER_01]: The opposition said Ted umpired his own ballgame.
[SPEAKER_01]: But he did know the strike zone, and he would not hit a black ball under any circumstances for anybody.
[SPEAKER_01]: He knew the strike zone.
[SPEAKER_01]: He was in that groove.
[SPEAKER_01]: And if it's close, they were with Ted,
[SPEAKER_01]: The umpire, not Latin, not old, but I'm sure he got some.
[SPEAKER_01]: For example, I was playing, I was pitching one day.
[SPEAKER_01]: Jack Kramer was pitching against me from St. Louis Browns.
[SPEAKER_01]: Later came over to Boston.
[SPEAKER_01]: And the first time up, the first pitch, he threw me a perfect curveball.
[SPEAKER_01]: What I thought was a perfect pitch.
[SPEAKER_01]: I think they must have taken a picture of it because he threw that same pitch right at the same place every time.
[SPEAKER_01]: But the umpire called me out on a pitch that was outside.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I told the umpire, I said, that wasn't a strike, the ball was outside.
[SPEAKER_01]: You know what he said?
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, it's just a matter of time.
[SPEAKER_01]: You ain't going to hit it.
[SPEAKER_02]: get it over with, you know.
[SPEAKER_01]: So that's the difference, you know, about the umpires.
[SPEAKER_01]: In other words, with some umpires, it don't make any difference.
[SPEAKER_01]: I'm not a good hitter, but just get it over with.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, I'll tell you a story about that too.
[SPEAKER_00]: When Yogi first came out,
[SPEAKER_01]: He had the reputation of being a good fastball hitter.
[SPEAKER_01]: You know, don't let him beat you with a fastball.
[SPEAKER_01]: All right.
[SPEAKER_01]: We get into a ballgame against the Yankees, been waiting for it.
[SPEAKER_01]: The wind's blowing in, he's left-handed.
[SPEAKER_01]: And it's about to get six in, and I got a four-nothing lead, two out and nobody on, and Yogi Bear comes in.
[SPEAKER_01]: This is the first game that I've seen.
[SPEAKER_01]: The catcher called for the curveball, and I shook him off, shook him off, got the fastball.
[SPEAKER_01]: I'm going to find out now.
[SPEAKER_01]: I'm a fastball pitcher.
[SPEAKER_01]: He's a fastball hitter.
[SPEAKER_01]: I'm going to find out whether my fastball is good enough to get him out.
[SPEAKER_01]: The first pitch, he fouled it fast.
[SPEAKER_01]: The catcher went through the same thing again, gave me everything but the fastball.
[SPEAKER_01]: I shook him off till I got the fastball.
[SPEAKER_01]: I came back with the fastball, above the knees, down the middle of the plate, that's me.
[SPEAKER_01]: I was throwing hard.
[SPEAKER_01]: He hit the thing and the teeth of the wind into the base of the bullpen and turned away hard.
[SPEAKER_01]: To this day, I haven't thrown hard to him since.
[SPEAKER_01]: A lot of people say he's a bad ball hitter.
[SPEAKER_01]: He was a fastball hitter.
[SPEAKER_01]: He wasn't a bad ball hitter.
[SPEAKER_01]: And you could throw him 19 change-ups and he's still hitting for the fastball with the big wagon top.
[SPEAKER_01]: And he's lunging, lunging out.
[SPEAKER_01]: And after he hit this home run, he proved to me that I couldn't hit fastball.
[SPEAKER_01]: I would show him the fastball where he couldn't hit it.
[SPEAKER_01]: But just, and he couldn't wait.
[SPEAKER_01]: He'd hit ground balls into the ground, and if he did, if he'd gotten the ball that sold him inside, if he got good wood on it, he was way out in front.
[SPEAKER_01]: He'd pull it back just a long strike.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I could never understand, even after I left baseball, why other pitchers didn't learn to not throw at the fastball.
[SPEAKER_01]: Don Newcombe, I remember this after.
[SPEAKER_01]: Don Newcombe won 28th of August.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yogi Berra hit three home runs off of Don Newcombe in the World Series that year, and two there in Boston.
[SPEAKER_01]: Newcombe couldn't throw a fastball by him, and he could throw one.
[SPEAKER_01]: But a lot of other pitchers that pitched against Yogi for years, they never did learn how to pitch.
[SPEAKER_02]: Who were some of the toughest hitters in the American league you faced, would you say?
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, I've been asked that question all the time.
[SPEAKER_01]: I'll start in reverse a little bit.
[SPEAKER_01]: The hitters that I loved to pitch to were the big free swingers that swung for the home run, and especially if they couldn't hit the ball up and in.
[SPEAKER_01]: The hitters that gave me trouble, that killed me dead,
[SPEAKER_01]: was the little left-hand here that hit the ball.
[SPEAKER_01]: You couldn't strike him out.
[SPEAKER_01]: He'd hit the ball where it's pitched to the opposite field.
[SPEAKER_01]: Nellie Fox, Johnny Pesky, those kind of guys, they wore me out.
[SPEAKER_01]: But the big freestylers, especially if they couldn't hit the ball up, I loved them.
[SPEAKER_01]: I was sitting in Fenway Park two years ago,
[SPEAKER_01]: after the old-timers came, when they gave us this watch.
[SPEAKER_01]: We're sitting way up here in the box, where they had to run these boxes inside.
[SPEAKER_01]: You'd go out here and watch the voting.
[SPEAKER_01]: Bobby Doerr and I were sitting here.
[SPEAKER_01]: And this Bill Balboni, the big Cleveland, I mean, the first one.
[SPEAKER_02]: Kansas City.
[SPEAKER_01]: Kansas City.
[SPEAKER_01]: Kansas City vote for Balboni.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I stole the door.
[SPEAKER_01]: I said,
[SPEAKER_01]: If I could pitch against nine like this guy, I would still be pitching.
[SPEAKER_01]: But, I told him, if I had to pitch against nine like Wade Boggs, I wouldn't even come to the ballpark.
[SPEAKER_01]: I'd stay at home.
[SPEAKER_01]: And while I'm talking, Balboni struck out.
[SPEAKER_01]: That's the kind of hitter I love.
[SPEAKER_01]: I struck out Rudy York one time in Detroit.
[SPEAKER_01]: He later came to our ball club.
[SPEAKER_01]: Rudy York was a long ball hitter.
[SPEAKER_01]: I struck out Rudy York three times on nine pitches.
[SPEAKER_01]: The first three times was bad.
[SPEAKER_01]: The fourth time he was supposed to hit, they took him out for a pinch hitter.
[SPEAKER_01]: He ripped rapidly from left hand hitting out for a hit for Rudy York.
[SPEAKER_01]: I struck him out three times on nine pitches.
[SPEAKER_01]: I just happened to get it there one of those days.
[SPEAKER_01]: I don't think he even fouled the ball.
[SPEAKER_01]: How about Greenberg?
[SPEAKER_01]: Greenberg was, I didn't pitch against him that much.
[SPEAKER_01]: But when I saw him, he had slowed up somewhat in his reflexes.
[SPEAKER_01]: And you could throw the fastball at him, especially if you crowd him a little bit.
[SPEAKER_01]: I'm not talking about how others...
[SPEAKER_01]: There's pitchers on the Red Sox ball club that ask me, how do you pitch so-and-so?
[SPEAKER_01]: I said, I pitch him inside.
[SPEAKER_01]: And they said, well, I pitch him inside and he wires me out.
[SPEAKER_01]: I said, yeah, but you're pitching him on the inside part of the plate for a strike.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I said, I'm pitching him this far inside the plate of the field.
[SPEAKER_01]: In on his hands.
[SPEAKER_01]: I broke a lot of backs.
[SPEAKER_01]: That was my mate.
[SPEAKER_01]: That's where I wanted to go.
[SPEAKER_01]: Until they proved that it could hit that far.
[SPEAKER_01]: I'll tell you a guy that gave me a lot of trouble for a right hander.
[SPEAKER_01]: that could hit me with his eye closed was George Kell.
[SPEAKER_01]: He was a good hitter.
[SPEAKER_01]: He was a hungry hitter, kind of like Enos Slurr.
[SPEAKER_01]: He never gave up a time to fight away.
[SPEAKER_01]: He was just up here all the time, aggressive all the time.
[SPEAKER_01]: I seen Bobby Doar, he'd come back to bench, angry at himself, said, I just wasn't thinking, I wasn't firing down, I just give up a time to fight away.
[SPEAKER_01]: George Carolina, Florida, they'd never give you a time.
[SPEAKER_01]: Pete Rose, never give us a time to fight away.
[SPEAKER_01]: They're looking for that baseball.
[SPEAKER_02]: Did you keep a book on the other batters, a regular book, or did you just have it all up here?
[SPEAKER_01]: No, I'll tell you what.
[SPEAKER_01]: I had it up here.
[SPEAKER_01]: I had one time back when I was pitching.
[SPEAKER_01]: I would take the line-up for my pitch against the Yankees tomorrow.
[SPEAKER_01]: I'd look at the line-up.
[SPEAKER_01]: After the ballgame, mentally, just like you had it taped here, and right by, I'd be laying down.
[SPEAKER_01]: If I pitched a good ballgame, I could recall each batter, say, went about four times, I could tell you
[SPEAKER_01]: Each time at bat, approximately what the count was, I could tell you where he hit the ball.
[SPEAKER_01]: Each time at bat, I could go through the whole ball clock system, after the ball game.
[SPEAKER_01]: If this man went to bat, I could tell you, well, the first time, DeMargio.
[SPEAKER_01]: Last December, yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: Ground ball and shortstop.
[SPEAKER_01]: Or double off the wall.
[SPEAKER_01]: I could tell you the time at bat, what he hit.
[SPEAKER_01]: approximately what the count was and where he hit the ball.
[SPEAKER_01]: After the ball game, then try to adjust.
[SPEAKER_00]: I've also read that some pitchers used to study box scores to see how certain hitters did against certain pitchers.
[SPEAKER_01]: Absolutely.
[SPEAKER_01]: I've done this extensively.
[SPEAKER_01]: Watch the box score and see
[SPEAKER_01]: Of course this, it can get carried too far and it can confuse the heck out of you.
[SPEAKER_01]: But I'd like to know if St. Louis Brown is beating somebody, what kind of picture was working against him?
[SPEAKER_01]: And who was successful against him?
[SPEAKER_01]: What type of picture?
[SPEAKER_01]: This says middle section, doesn't it?
[SPEAKER_01]: But also you want to know,
[SPEAKER_01]: if you're pitching, you want to know who's hitting good on that ballclub and who isn't.
[SPEAKER_01]: I would walk out of 275 or 80 innings, I would walk maybe 50.
[SPEAKER_01]: But over half of those would be, to me, not ordered by the manager, would be intentional.
[SPEAKER_01]: I'm pitching around.
[SPEAKER_01]: However,
[SPEAKER_01]: What amazes me, I sit here and watch TV, all these announcers are giving the pitcher credit.
[SPEAKER_01]: And last night they said, well, he worked him outside, then he worked him inside, ball two.
[SPEAKER_01]: The announcer is giving the pitcher credit for doing just exactly what he wanted to.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, he was trying to throw a strike, trying to get the ball over the plate, that's all he was trying to do.
[SPEAKER_01]: He wasn't working him this way or working him that way.
[SPEAKER_00]: I know.
[SPEAKER_01]: But most of the cases I did, I was throwing for a strike.
[SPEAKER_01]: I wanted to get ahead of that hitter.
[SPEAKER_01]: I didn't nibble, I didn't fool around.
[SPEAKER_01]: And if I ever walked that first man, you might as well put him on a scoreboard.
[SPEAKER_01]: It seemed like it.
[SPEAKER_01]: Score in third.
[SPEAKER_01]: But the times come when, there are the times when
[SPEAKER_01]: I remember this thing.
[SPEAKER_01]: The worst hitting pitcher in American League.
[SPEAKER_01]: I walked him on four pitches leading off three.
[SPEAKER_01]: I was close, but I just couldn't find the play.
[SPEAKER_01]: The last time I just aimed the damn ball.
[SPEAKER_01]: Who was that incidentally?
[SPEAKER_01]: I don't remember.
[SPEAKER_01]: Johnny Brooker?
[SPEAKER_00]: I don't remember.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, Johnny Brooker.
[SPEAKER_01]: But he was an out man, you might say, a saint.
[SPEAKER_01]: Sometimes I would do this.
[SPEAKER_01]: work extra hard to make that pitcher lead off so I got him.
[SPEAKER_01]: Or if there's two good hitters, left-hand hitters, give me trouble hitting three and four, I'd try my best to split those two so I don't have to face both of them in one inning.
[SPEAKER_02]: What happened to Boo Ferris?
[SPEAKER_02]: He came up, then he went down.
[SPEAKER_02]: Just didn't last long, did he?
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, Boo Ferris was a heck of a boy.
[SPEAKER_01]: He came up,
[SPEAKER_01]: He got out of the service.
[SPEAKER_01]: He was at Randolph Field out there.
[SPEAKER_01]: He came to Boston in 45.
[SPEAKER_01]: He won 20 and so he grew up.
[SPEAKER_01]: From 46 to the end of my career, I roomed with him.
[SPEAKER_01]: He's a fine gentleman, a Southern Baptist or Methodist or something.
[SPEAKER_01]: He never used curse words, never drank smoke or anything.
[SPEAKER_01]: He won 25 and lost 6 in 46.
[SPEAKER_01]: But he came up with arm problems.
[SPEAKER_01]: Now there's a man that could throw the same type of pitch I'm talking about, the Dyson type of throw.
[SPEAKER_01]: His was better.
[SPEAKER_01]: He broke a little bit.
[SPEAKER_01]: But he threw a heavy ball, that old thing.
[SPEAKER_01]: He could throw it and run it.
[SPEAKER_01]: And Boo didn't have a good curveball, didn't have a good changer.
[SPEAKER_01]: But he threw, just warming up with him, the old ball was heavy, kind of boring him.
[SPEAKER_01]: But he came up with some arm trouble problems.
[SPEAKER_01]: He was a good athlete, pretty good hitter.
[SPEAKER_02]: Where does he live?
[SPEAKER_01]: In Mississippi.
[SPEAKER_01]: He's been coaching at some college there.
[SPEAKER_01]: He stayed with the Red Sox for a while as a coach.